forcetalks.com 2019-04-28

# Salesforce | Privacy Policy - Forcetalks

## 1\. FORCETALKS Privacy Statement. effective as of January 1, 2016

Forcetalks (“Forcetalks” or the “Company”) is committed to protecting the privacy of every individual who visit the Company’s Web site (“Website Visitors”) and individuals who are actively or inactively registered to use the Services (“Clients”). This Privacy Statement elaborates Forcetalks’ privacy practices related to the use of the Company’s Web site and the applications and services offered by Forcetalks (the “Services”).

Although generally a Website Visitor is under no obligation to share or provide personal information while accessing the Forcetalks site, there are some circumstances under which a User may be requested to provide such information.

## 2\. Information collected

Forcetalks requires you to provide the Company with personal contact information, such as your full name, company name, phone number, and email address, in the case when expressing an interest in obtaining information about Services or to register to use the Services.

Forcetalks may collect information through the use of popular information-gathering tools called Web beacons and cookies. This includes information from your Web browser such as browser type, browser language, your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the view/click actions you take on the Company’s Web site.

## 3\. Use of information

Forcetalks uses data of Website Visitors to better the services being requested by user.

The Company may also consider using Data about Forcetalks users for marketing purposes. For example, if you have agreed for the Company to send you information regarding the Company and its partners, affiliates and events, the Company can ask you or send notification seeking permission.

To operate and improve the Company’s website, it may use Web Site Navigational Information itself or this along with Forcetalks Clients’ Data to provide personalized information about the Company.

## 4\. Web Site Navigational

 **Cookies, Web Beacons and IP Addresses**  
Forcetalks may collect information through the use of popular information-gathering tools namely Web beacons and cookies. This includes information from your Web browser such as browser type, browser language, your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the view/click actions you take on the Company’s Web site. This section describes clearly the types of Web Site Navigational Information that the Company may use and how this information may be used.

 **Cookies**

Forcetalks encourages optimization targeting easy and meaningful interactions on the Company’s website with the help of cookies. When you visit one of the Company’s Web site, Forcetalks’ servers will then send a cookie to your machine. Cookies do not personally identify you but they only recognize you with the help of your Web browser. You remain anonymous to the Company unless you choose to identify yourself to Forcetalks via filling out a Web form, creating an account or contacting the Forcetalks team.  
Forcetalks uses session-based and persistent-based cookies. Session cookies disappear from your computer as you close your browser software or switch off your computer. Persistent cookies however remain on your computer after you close browser or switch off your computer. Please note after disabling your browser’s ability to accept cookies, you may not be able to use all the Services successfully but you can still browse the Company’s Web site.

Find below a list of different categories of cookies:

### 4.1. Required Cookies

Required cookies are essential to operate the Company’s Web site along with Services and hence there is no option to opt out of these cookies.

These cookies enable you to navigate and use all the features of the Forcetalks Web site, especially accessing secure and protected areas of the Web site and using Forcetalks Services.

### 4.2. Performance cookies

These cookies collect information about how the Website Visitors use our Web site. Such cookies however do not collect information that individually identifies a Visitor. All the information these cookies do collect is aggregated and anonymous. It can help improve how the Company’s Web site functions and performs.

You can opt out of performance cookies by [clicking here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

### 4.3. Functionality cookies

These cookies help the Company’s Web site retain information you have entered or choices you have selected such as your username, language, or your region. This helps the Company provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies also help you optimize your use of Forcetalks’s Services after logging in.

Forcetalks uses Flash cookies (local shared objects), to store your preferences on the basis of your view or activities on our Web site to personalize your visit.

To learn how to unsubscribe and get rid of these functionality cookies, [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). Opting out may affect the functionality you receive when visiting Forcetalks.

You can manage privacy for Flash cookies by [clicking here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118).

### 4.4. Targeting or Advertising cookies

Forcetalks engages third Forcetalks time-to-time uses cookies delivered by third parties to track the performance of advertisements. Forcetalks does not contract with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses or Web beacons on the Company’s Web site, from emails, and on 4rd party Web sites.

To learn more about opt out instructions, [click here](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

To learn how to manage privacy for Flash cookies, [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118).

### 4.5. Web Beacons

Forcetalks uses Web beacons to improve Company’s Web site and communication by email.This can be utilized in alone or in conjunction with cookies to gather information about Clients and Website Visitors’ usage of the Company’s Web site.

### 4.6. IP Addresses

When you visit Forcetalks’s Web site, the Company collects your Internet Protocol or IP addresses to track and aggregate non-personal information. For example, Forcetalks uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which Clients and Website Visitors browse the Company’s Web site.

### 4.7. Social Media Features

Forcetalks may use some social media features such as the Twitter ‘tweet’ button (“Social Media Features”). Such features may collect your IP address along with providing which page you are visiting on the Company’s Web site, and may set a cookie to allow particular features to function properly. You may be asked by such Social Media Features to post information on the Company’s Web site to your profile page provided by some third party Social Media network to share with your network.

## 5\. Public forums

Forcetalks may provide blogs, discussion forums or chat rooms on Forcetalks. Any information, personal or otherwise, you choose to post in such a forum may be read, saved or used by others who visit these forums and may send you unsolicited messages. Forcetalks is not responsible for any personal information you share on such pages.

## 6\. Transfer of Information

The Company primarily stores Data in India. To help facilitate Forcetalks’ global operations, the Company may transfer information from one place to another and this Privacy Statement shall apply even if Forcetalks transfers Data About Forcetalks Clients to countries around the Globe.

## 7\. Communications preferences

Forcetalks offers Website Visitors and Clients a means to choose how the Company uses the information provided. If you provide Forcetalks with contact information, you can manage how the Company uses your information. To get rid of incoming mails from Forcetalks, you have provision to click on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of the Company’s marketing emails.

## 8\. Security

Forcetalks uses robust security measures to protect your Data.

## 9\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

Forcetalks reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement. Forcetalks shall notify about changes to this Privacy Statement via the Company’s Web site at least thirty business days prior to the change(s) taking effect.

## 10 Contacting us

Have any questions regarding this Privacy Statement? Have a question on the information practices of the Forcetalks Web site? Do direct them at [support@forcetalks.com](mailto:support@forcetalks.com)
